曾經在某地 有位擁有神奇力量的和尚
他所畫的畫就像有生命一般 能自由活動
人們都覺得毛骨悚然
和尚越來越難以跟別人相處
於是他就孤身一人 安靜地躲在山中過日子
古都 黑兔回憶錄
I think of how it all was made
我思考著這一切是如何被創造的
Each detail of this world portrayed
描寫了這世界每一個細節
In bursts of color, every sight and sound
連接出現的無數色彩 一切的景象和聲音
The wide blue sky and the immobile ground
還有廣闊的藍天與穩固的大地
It's all too great to understand
這一切偉大得讓人難以理解
The moon, with one stroke of his hand
在他著下一筆後
Started to glow and all the stars appeared
明月開始發出光亮 並出現眾多繁星
How did it all end up here
這奇跡究竟如何產生
I am here at this crucial time
我在關鍵時刻來到此處
Hope I find what I came to find
希望我能找到我來找尋的
I'm destined to be, the way I'm meant to be
這是註定好的 也是必須發生的
I have to find my way
我一定要找到我路
This is the secret of my life
這是我一生的秘密
Learn to love and always seek for what is right
學懂去愛 與永能找出正確的事
And learn all things change, some flowers die while others grow
與瞭解世上的所有變化 有些花會枯萎但也有花順利成長
Some gifts are only seen, not held
而某些事物只能可見 卻無法擁有
There are lots of things I still don't know
還有很多事情是我無法知曉
I feel your gentle smile sometimes
我有時能感覺到你溫柔的笑容
But know I can't go back in time
但要知道我是無法回到過去
I won't fight even all these lonely tears
我甚至不會壓抑所有寂寞的淚水
Cause they allow me to be close to you
因為它們令我更加親近你
Summer turns cold, red leaves fly by
夏天結束天氣轉涼 紅葉落下開始起舞
Seasons change but they don't ask why
四季轉變 但它們不問原因
All part of this maze, long nights before the dawn
所有都在迷陣中 黎明前的漫漫長夜
And I have your song
而我有你的歌聲
This is the secret of my life
這是我一生的秘密
Learn to love and always seek for what is right
學懂去愛 與永能找出正確的事
And learn all things change, some flowers die while others grow
與瞭解世上的所有變化 有些花會枯萎但也有花順利成長
Some gifts are only seen, not held
而某些事物只能見得 無法擁有
Seldom understood, but felt
能理解的不多 但能感受到
乖乖 別哭哦
我們肯定會再見的
說好了
I know that you must think of me
我知道你定會想起我
So you are never far
所以你永遠不會遠離我
I can be where you are
我能知道你在何方
This is the secret of my life
這是我一生的秘密
Learn to love and always seek for what is right
學懂去愛 與永能找出正確的事
All life must change, just like water falls and turns to clouds again
所有生命都必須改變 就像雨點從天落下後又能轉化為白雲
Some gifts are lost and some return
會丟失某些事物 某些又會歸來
There are lots of things I still must learn
還有太多事情是我需要去學習
SGS曙光社字幕組製作
歌詞：solosodium賢伉儷、Kangaroo、紅姐姐賢伉儷、諸位美國友人 繁化：龍之戒
這就結束了?
這個啊 誰知道呢